Here, we're going to be pulling together a lot of the points from throughout this lesson.
在这个视频中 我们将综合运用前面学习的内容
In this first part,
首先
you can see that we're just reading in the libraries and the dataset used for this.
还是照样导入需要的库和数据
I'm going to skip some of these questions that were just like fill in the blanks.
我会跳过一些问题的讲解 比如这里只是填充对应的文字
But, one of the main things that I want to go through
主要讲解大家在之前视频里 没有见过的内容
So, right here, you were supposed to write a function that basically follows these steps.
这里 你要根据这些步骤编写一个函数
So, you drop the rows associated with salary,
首先 将 Salary 列存在缺失值的数据删除
you split off the response,
拆分出目标变量
and then you also drop a whole bunch of things and create a new X matrix.
然后删除一些变量 构建 X 矩阵
You take the numeric variables and fill in the mean.
筛选出数值型变量 用均值填充缺失值
So a lot of these things we did earlier, right.
很多之前做过的操作
So we filled in the mean in an earlier part.
比如 用均值填充缺失值
In this part, you dummy the categorical variables,
这一部分 你创建了虚拟变量
so you did that in an earlier part as well,
同样也在之前做过
and you were basically just creating this clean X and
然后就得到了整洁的 X 矩阵 和 y 向量
And the last part of this was to take a look at
这部分最后的内容就是看一下
how well the linear model fit with different cut offs for X and Y.
不同截断情况的 X 和 y 对应的线性模型表现如何
So, you'll notice that this is pulling from a file in the back and I
你也许注意到了 这里其实是调用了一个函数
just want to go through sort of how that file looks.
我们可以到定义函数的文件里看一下
And you'll see this is the fine optimal LM function that you were running.
你可以看到刚才调用的 fine_optimal_lm 函数
And so, you can see these are the inputs that it takes.
这些是函数的输入值
But essentially, right here,
这里的代码
it's just creating a whole bunch of MD things that it's going to
其实就是创建了一些空的列表、字典等
work with throughout this.
供整个函数使用
It's going to run through a whole bunch of cut offs.
这里是遍历所有的截断点
So, the cut offs are basically how many missing values there were in any particular row.
截断点就是指允许某一列存在缺失值 (非 0 值) 的数量
So, the smaller the cut offs the more features that end up in your X matrix,
截断点值越小 X 里包含的特征数就越多
and the larger the cut off the fewer features end up in your X matrix.
截断点值越大 X 里的特征数就越少
So you can see basically that's what's happening right here is,
这里可以看到对截断点的应用
you're reducing the X matrix based on, so,
你在根据截断点减小 X 的大小
X sum, and it's not the number of missing features,
这个 X.sum 并不是缺失值的数量
it's what proportion we're ones.
而是 列中数据为 1 的总数
So, if X had a whole bunch of ones in it,
如果 X 中的某列虚拟变量有很多 1
then that means there is
那就说明该组数据
hopefully enough variability to tell one group from another group.
有希望存在足够的可变性 与其他类别进行区分
Whereas, if there was only three ones,
与之相对 如果某列虚拟变量只有三个 1
that might suggest that it would be really hard to use
那很可能意味着 该列特征很难用于
that feature to predict some sort of continuous response.
预测某个连续的目标变量
And that's likely that that might be a feature that helps the model overfit.
而这样的特征也很可能是 模型出现过拟合的原因
Then, right here, we're just doing a train to split,
这里又是对数据进行测试集和训练集的划分
we fit our model.
训练模型
So it's just fitting the model with the reduced X
我们使用的是经过筛选的 X
up here and then it's appending the R-squared values off of it.
然后把 R 平方值追加到这个列表里
So, it's going to run this process for a whole bunch of
对不同规模的 X 矩阵迭代这一流程
different X matrices and then this is the plot that you're going to get out at the end,
下面的代码会绘制出一个图表
if you decide to plot it.
如果你想画的话 (通过 plot 参数控制)
So, it's going to return all of the R-squared on the training in
最后 函数会返回所有的 R 平方值 包括训练集和测试集的评分
test sets and it will return the linear model,
还会返回线性模型
the X train, X test, Y train,
表现最好模型对应的 X_train、X_test、y_train、y_test
So, these parts are only coming back for the best model
这部分只会返回表现最好的那一组数据集
in basically each of the runs through a different set of cut offs.
对于不同截断点创建的不同数据集来说
It says, "Only choose the X where it was the best cut off".
这里就是 根据 best_cutoff 筛选 X 矩阵
Which is basically where the R-squared value was the best on the test set.
根据上面这句代码选出测试集 R 平方最大值对应的截断点
So, we care about how this extends to new data.
因为我们在意的是模型在新数据 (测试集) 上的扩展性
So hopefully that makes sense.
希望大家能理解
What's happening in this function back here?
这个函数在后台完成了什么操作
So, again, we're going to run that function.
再次运行这里的代码
We're going to pass it all of the X and Y.
传入所有的 X 和 y
It's going to give us back the best parts for this,
然后它会返回表现最好的部分
and then all of the R-squared for each of these different thresholds.
还有所有截断点对应的 R 平方值
Again, the higher the value,
这个值越高
it might seem sort of backwards,
再说一下截断点的意义
but this is the number of ones a column needs to have.
这是一列中最少要包含的 1 值的数量
So, the higher the value,
也就是说 这个值越高
the fewer the number of features in the model,
模型包含的特征就越少
the lower the value the more features are in your X matrix.
值越小 X 中的特征就越多
And again, it's looping through all of those things,
因为函数要对这些值进行迭代
so it could take a little time,
所以运行需要一些时间
but you should see something that looks sort of like this.
不过 最后你应该能够看到这样的结果
So you can see, as the number of features increases,
可以看到 一开始随着特征数量的增加
it gets better to a point but then,
模型的表现会越来越好 直到某个点
once you hit too many features in
当你向 X 矩阵中加入太多特征时
your X matrix you start to overfit and your test data starts to fall.
模型就开始出现过拟合 测试集上的表现开始下降
And actually, if you decrease this even a little bit more,
事实上 如果你在这里减少更多值
if you changed it to like 20,
比如将其修改为 20
what I saw were massive drop-offs in the test data.
测试集的线条会直线下滑
So, the training data set kept going towards one or even hit one.
训练集上的表现可能还会上升 甚至到达 1
But in the test data,
但在测试集上
this would fall down to like negative some crazy number.
就会出现急剧地下滑 甚至出现负值
But this is actually a pretty common pattern for R-squared or
不过 这里看到的趋势其实是 R 平方值评分的常见模式
for mean squared error you frequently see at the opposite direction.
如果是均方误差 你很可能会看到相反方向的趋势
Again, what we care about is how well were fitting on the test set.
重要的是 我们在乎的是模型在测试集上的表现
So, the best on our test sets is basically held within these parts.
表现最好的模型以及数据集 是在这几个变量中
So, with that we could answer these questions down here.
接下来就可以回答下面的问题了
Because we're using a ridge regression model,
因为我们使用的是岭回归
one of the best ways to tell which X features matter in our model,
最好的评估特征重要性的方法其实
is to look at the weight of their coefficients.
就是看每个特征系数的权重
Because our features are normalized,
因为特征都经过了标准化处理
we can just look at how large the coefficient is.
所以只要比较系数的大小就可以了
So, the negative or positive is still associated with the direction,
值的正负说明方向
the directional impact on the response associated with that particular variable,
方向是指 特征变量对预测变量的影响是正面的反面的
and the size of the coefficient is basically
绝对值大小代表的是
the impact it has even after being normalized.
标准化之后的特征影响程度
So, you can see, in terms of being a developer country appears to
可以看到 对于开发者来说
be a very influential item as well as how many years of experience.
居住国家以及工作年限 都是对工资影响较大的因素
But it isn't the case that the more years of experience you have,
但并不是说 工作的时间越长
the higher you will get paid.
工资就会越高
It looks like if you have more than 20 years of experience that's pretty
好像工作经验 18-19 年对工资的影响要比 20 年及以上的高
But there are the 12 to 13 make more than this 19 to 20,
工作经验 12-13 年的比 19-20 年的影响要高
and more than the 13 to 14,
并且还高于 13-14 年的
and more than the 15 to 16.
还高于 15-16 年的
So, it's not directly related according to this model.
也就是说 年限和影响强度不是线性的关系
And you'll also notice again that where you
你还会发现 作为开发者
live determines how much you make as a developer.
居住地也会对工资有很大影响
So, there are certain countries where you're
某些国家的开发者工资
better paid as a developer than in other countries.
要比其他国家高
Those seem to be the two largest indicators.
这些看上去是最重要的两个特征
Yes. And with that,
好的
you can use that information to help fill in some of these parts.
你可以用刚刚分析的信息来完成这里的一些练习
But the main takeaway from this last part is basically this image,
这节课最重要的内容其实是这个图表
and sort of the idea that's associated with it.
以及它揭示的现象
That the more features you have doesn't necessarily mean that
并不是特征越多
you'll get a model that will work better in practice, but rather,
模型就能获得更好的表现
you should have a model that has features that are actually indicators
你应该用那些跟目标变量相关的特征
of the response and indicators of how they influence the response.
作为模型的预测变量
And if you keep throwing in more and more stuff into your model,
如果向模型中盲目添加特征
at some point it can overfit to the extent
最终会造成过拟合
that you won't be able to extend your model to new data very well,
使模型没办法扩展到新的数据
you'll only predict well on the training data.
只能在训练集上表现良好